{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "You can check the conditions against __________ when applying conditional formatting",
            "optionA": "  Cell value ",
            "optionB": "  Formula ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can check the conditions against Cell value or Formula when applying conditional formatting. ",
            "keyString": "639666s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not true regarding Conditional Formatting?",
            "optionA": "  You can add more than one condition to check ",
            "optionB": "  You can set condition to look for Bold and apply Italics on them ",
            "optionC": "  You can apply Font, border and pattern formats that meets the specified conditions ",
            "optionD": "  You can delete any condition from Conditional Formatting dialog box if it is not requried ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Conditional Formatting we cannot set condition to look for Bold and apply Italics on them. ",
            "keyString": "639699s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is invalid statement?",
            "optionA": "  Sheet tabs can be colored ",
            "optionB": "  Some picture can be applied as a background of a sheet ",
            "optionC": "  You can set the column width automatically fit the amount of text ",
            "optionD": "  The width of a row and be specified manually or fit automatically ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe width of a row and be specified manually or fit automatically is invalid statement. ",
            "keyString": "639713s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use the formula palette to",
            "optionA": "  Format cells containing numbers ",
            "optionB": "  Create and edit formula containing functions ",
            "optionC": "  Enter assumptions data ",
            "optionD": "  Copy a range of cells ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFormula palette is used to create and edit formula. Itisalsopossibletotypeafunctiondirectlyintoacell,however,asthereareover300 functionsbuiltintoMicrosoftExcel,someofwhicharequitecomplex,Excelprovidesthe Formula Palette to simplify the process.",
            "keyString": "639726s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a range is selected, how can you activate the previous cell?",
            "optionA": "  Press the Alt key ",
            "optionB": "  Press Tab ",
            "optionC": "  Press Enter ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo go to previous cell we use Go To function Ctrl + G. ",
            "keyString": "639738s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use drag-and-drop to embed excel worksheet data in a word document",
            "optionA": "  By dragging a range of excel data to the word button on the taskbar while pressing the Ctrl key ",
            "optionB": "  By dragging a range of excel data to the word button on the taskbar while pressing Shift key ",
            "optionC": "  By dragging a range of excel data to the word button on the taskbar while pressing Alt key ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can use drag-and-drop to embed excel worksheet data in a word document by dragging a range of excel data to the word button on the taskbar while pressing the Ctrl key. ",
            "keyString": "683440s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The auto calculate feature",
            "optionA": "  Can only add values in a range of cells ",
            "optionB": "  Provides a quick way to view the result of an arithmetic operation on a range of cells ",
            "optionC": "  Automatically creates formulas and adds them to a worksheet ",
            "optionD": "  A and C ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe auto calculate feature provides a quick way to view the result of an arithmetic operation on a range of cells. ",
            "keyString": "683475s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Excel uniquely identifies cells within a worksheet with a cell name",
            "optionA": "  Cell names ",
            "optionB": "  Column numbers and row letters ",
            "optionC": "  Column letters and row numbers ",
            "optionD": "  Cell locator coordinates ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tColumn letters and row numbers in Excel uniquely identifies cells within a worksheet with a cell name. ",
            "keyString": "683493s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Delete key of keyboard is assigned to which command in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Edit > Clear > Contents ",
            "optionB": "  Edit > Clear > All ",
            "optionC": "  Edit > Delete ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Delete key of keyboard is assigned to Clear Contents command in Excel. Clear Contents will clear only the data, will not clear any formats. ",
            "keyString": "748337s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If you need to remove only the formatting done in a range (numbers and formula typed there should not be removed), you must",
            "optionA": "  From Edit menu choose Clear and then Formats ",
            "optionB": "  From Edit menu choose Delete ",
            "optionC": "  Click on Remove Formatting tool on Standard Toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  Double click the Format Painter and then press Esc key in keyboard ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIf we need to remove only the formatting done in a range, we must use From Edit menu choose Clear and then Formats. ",
            "keyString": "748511s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "By default Excel provides 3 worksheets. You need only two of them, how will you delete the third one?",
            "optionA": "  Right click on Sheet Tab of third sheet and choose Delete from the context menu ",
            "optionB": "  Click on Sheet 3 and from Edit menu choose Delete ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRight-click the tab and choose Delete from its shortcut menu in All version of excel. In Microsoft Excel 2010 onwards Choose Home > Delete > Delete Sheet on the Ribbon, press Alt+HDS Microsoft Excel 2007 and earlier Press \u2018ALT\u2019 + \u2018E\u2019, then the \u2018L\u2019 key. ",
            "keyString": "748872s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following action removes a sheet from workbook?",
            "optionA": "  Select the sheet, then choose Edit > Delete Sheet ",
            "optionB": "  Select the sheet then choose Format > Sheet > Hide ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo removes a sheet from workbook select the sheet, then choose Edit > Delete Sheet these options available in excel 2003 and earlier version. In Microsoft Excel 2007 onward Choose Home > Delete > Delete Sheet on the Ribbon. ",
            "keyString": "748949s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "While Finding and Replacing some data in Excel, which of the following statement is valid?",
            "optionA": "  You can Find and Replace within the sheet or workbook ",
            "optionB": "  Excel does not have option to match case for find ",
            "optionC": "  Both are valid ",
            "optionD": "  None are valid ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel we can Find and Replace within the sheet or workbook.",
            "keyString": "748987s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Getting data from a cell located in a different sheet is called ________",
            "optionA": "  Accessing ",
            "optionB": "  Referencing ",
            "optionC": "  Updating ",
            "optionD": "  Functioning ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGetting data from a cell located in a different sheet is called Cell reference. There are Three types of Cell reference in ExcelRelativeAbsoluteMixed",
            "keyString": "819780s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Tab scrolling button",
            "optionA": "  Allow you to view a different worksheet ",
            "optionB": "  Allow you to view additional worksheet rows down ",
            "optionC": "  Allow you to view additional worksheet columns to the right ",
            "optionD": "  Allow you to view additional sheets tabs ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTab scrolling button allow us to view additional sheets tabs. ",
            "keyString": "820243s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A numeric value can be treated as a label value if it precedes with",
            "optionA": "  Apostrophe (') ",
            "optionB": "  Exclamation (!) ",
            "optionC": "  Hash (#) ",
            "optionD": "  Ampersand (&) ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn apostrophe before a cell value forces Excel to interpret the value as label. This is mostly useful for values that look like a number or date. ",
            "keyString": "820597s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Concatenation of text can be done using",
            "optionA": "  Apostrophe (') ",
            "optionB": "  Exclamation (!) ",
            "optionC": "  Hash (#) ",
            "optionD": "  Ampersand (&) ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tConcatenation of text can be done using Ampersand (&). ",
            "keyString": "820937s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Data can be arranged in a worksheet in a easy to understand manner using",
            "optionA": "  Auto formatting ",
            "optionB": "  Applying styles ",
            "optionC": "  Changing fonts ",
            "optionD": "  all of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tData can be arranged in a worksheet in a easy to understand manner using all or any of the above options. ",
            "keyString": "821267s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following will not cut information?",
            "optionA": "  Pressing Ctrl + C ",
            "optionB": "  Selecting Edit > Cut from the menu ",
            "optionC": "  Clicking the Cut button on the standard ",
            "optionD": "  Pressing Ctrl+X ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPressing Ctrl+C when one or more cell is highlighted copies the cell's contents into the clipboard. ",
            "keyString": "883641s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a way to complete a cell entry?",
            "optionA": "  Pressing enter ",
            "optionB": "  Pressing any arrow key on the keyboard ",
            "optionC": "  Clicking the Enter button on the Formula bar ",
            "optionD": "  Pressing spacebar ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we press the spacebar, it selects the current cell for editing. ",
            "keyString": "883917s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can activate a cell by",
            "optionA": "  Pressing the Tab key ",
            "optionB": "  Clicking the cell ",
            "optionC": "  Pressing an arrow key ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA cell can be ready to activate by any of the method Pressing the Tab key or Clicking the cell or Pressing an arrow key. ",
            "keyString": "886719s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Text formulas:",
            "optionA": "  Replace cell references ",
            "optionB": "  Return ASCII values of characters ",
            "optionC": "  Concatenate and manipulate text ",
            "optionD": "  Show formula error value ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tConcatenate and manipulate text ",
            "keyString": "886958s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you insert a row?",
            "optionA": "  Right-click the row heading where you want to insert the new row and select Insert from the shortcut menu ",
            "optionB": "  Select the row heading where you want to insert the new row and select Edit >Row from the menu ",
            "optionC": "  Select the row heading where you want to insert the new row and click the Insert Row button on the standard toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRight-click the row heading where you want to insert the new row and select Insert from the shortcut menu in Excel 2003.Form 2007 and higher version Home > Insert > Insert Sheet Rows. ",
            "keyString": "888239s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can merge the main document with data source in Excel. In mail merge operation, Word is usually",
            "optionA": "  Server ",
            "optionB": "  Source ",
            "optionC": "  Client ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tYou can merge the main document with data source in Excel. In mail merge operation, Word is usually Client ",
            "keyString": "940197s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you update the values of formula cells if Auto Calculate mode of Excel is disabled?",
            "optionA": "  F8 ",
            "optionB": "  F9 ",
            "optionC": "  F10 ",
            "optionD": "  F11 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tManual calculation mode means that Excel will only recalculate all open workbooks when we request it by pressing F9. It allows to choose whether we want to update formulas in worksheets or entire workbook. ",
            "keyString": "940358s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You want to set such that when you type Baishakh and drag the fill handle, Excel should produce Jestha, Aashadh and so on. What will you set to effect that?",
            "optionA": "  Custom List ",
            "optionB": "  Auto Fill Options ",
            "optionC": "  Fill Across Worksheet ",
            "optionD": "  Fill Series ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUse a Custom list to sort or fill in a user-defined order. Excel provides day-of-the-week and month-of-the year built-in lists, but we can also create your own custom list. For Excel 2010 and later, click File > Options > Advanced > General > Edit Custom Lists. For Excel 2007, click the Microsoft Office Button Office button > Excel Options > Popular >Top options for working with Excel > Edit Custom Lists. ",
            "keyString": "940412s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Where can you change automatic or manual calculation mode in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Double CAL indicator on status bar ",
            "optionB": "  Go to File > Options > Formulas > Calculation Option - and mark the corresponding radio button ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen you press F9 or click Calc Sheet on the Calculation tab on the Tools/Options menu. Calculation also occurs every time that you save the file if you have the checkbox \"Recalculate workbook before saving\" checked under File > Options > Formulas. ",
            "keyString": "940459s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you show or hide the gridlines in Excel Worksheet?",
            "optionA": "  Go to Tools > Options > View tab and mark or remove the check box named Gridline ",
            "optionB": "  Click Gridline tool on Forms toolbar ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel 2016, 2013, 2010, 2007, click on View > Show > Gridlines For Excel 2003 and Earlier: Navigate to Tools > Options or Click Gridline tool on Forms toolbar. ",
            "keyString": "940503s13m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In EXCEL, you can sum a large range of data by simply selecting a tool button called ________.",
            "optionA": "  AutoFill ",
            "optionB": "  Auto correct ",
            "optionC": "  Auto sum ",
            "optionD": "  Auto format ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAutoSum is a Microsoft Excel function that adds together a range of cells and displays the total in the cell below the selected range.",
            "keyString": "588s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To select an entire column in MS-EXCEL, press?",
            "optionA": "  CTRL + C ",
            "optionB": "  CTRL + Arrow key ",
            "optionC": "  CTRL + S ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo select an entire column in MS-EXCEL, Click the column heading letter or press CTRL + Space Bar key. ",
            "keyString": "641s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To return the remainder after a number is divided by a divisor in EXCEL we use the function?",
            "optionA": "  ROUND ( ) ",
            "optionB": "  FACT ( ) ",
            "optionC": "  MOD ( ) ",
            "optionD": "  DIV ( ) ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe MOD function in Excel is used to find remainder after division of one number (dividend) by another (divisor). In mathematics, this operation is called the modulo operation or modulus, hence the name MOD. ",
            "keyString": "663s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which function is not available in the Consolidate dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Pmt ",
            "optionB": "  Average ",
            "optionC": "  Max ",
            "optionD": "  Sum ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution: ",
            "keyString": "686s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is not the function of \"Edit, Clear\" command?",
            "optionA": "  Delete contents ",
            "optionB": "  Delete notes ",
            "optionC": "  Delete cells ",
            "optionD": "  Delete formats ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution: ",
            "keyString": "718s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not true about Find and Replace in Excel",
            "optionA": "  You can search for bold and replace with italics ",
            "optionB": "  You can decide whether to look for the whole word or not ",
            "optionC": "  You can search in formula too ",
            "optionD": "  You can search by rows or columns or sheets ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution: ",
            "keyString": "46335s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can move a sheet from one workbook into new book by",
            "optionA": "  From Edit menu choose Move or Copy sheet, mark the Create a ccopy and Click OK ",
            "optionB": "  From Edit menu choose Move of Copy then choose (Move to end) and click OK ",
            "optionC": "  From Edit menu choose Move or Copy then select (new book) from To Book list and click OK ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFrom Edit menu choose Move or Copy then select (new book) from To Book list and click OK ",
            "keyString": "46463s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the shortcut key to replace a data with another in sheet?",
            "optionA": "  Ctrl + R ",
            "optionB": "  Ctrl + Shift + R ",
            "optionC": "  Ctrl + H ",
            "optionD": "  Ctrl + F ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:Ctrl + H shortcut key is usedto replace a data with another in sheet. ",
            "keyString": "46513s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Comments can be added to cells using ________",
            "optionA": "  Home > Comments ",
            "optionB": "  Insert > Comment ",
            "optionC": "  Data > Comments ",
            "optionD": "  View > Comments ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tComments can be added to cells using Insert > Comment. ",
            "keyString": "46549s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which menu option can be used to split windows into two?",
            "optionA": "  Review > Window ",
            "optionB": "  View > Window > Split ",
            "optionC": "  Window > Split ",
            "optionD": "  View > Split ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:View > Window > Split option can be used to split windows into two. ",
            "keyString": "46586s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you link data maintained in an excel workbook to a word document",
            "optionA": "  The word document cannot be edit ",
            "optionB": "  The word document contains a reference to the original source application ",
            "optionC": "  The word document must contain a hyperlink ",
            "optionD": "  The word document contains a copy of the actual data ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we link data maintained in an excel workbook to a word document the document contains a reference to the original source application. ",
            "keyString": "121856s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which area in an excel window allows entering values and formulas",
            "optionA": "  Title bar ",
            "optionB": "  Menu bar ",
            "optionC": "  Formula bar ",
            "optionD": "  Standard toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFormula Bar is where data or formulas we enter into a worksheet appear for the active cell. The Formula Bar can also be used to edit data or formula in the active cell. ",
            "keyString": "121891s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To hold row and column titles in place so that they do not scroll when you scroll a worksheet click the",
            "optionA": "  Unfreeze panes command on the window menu ",
            "optionB": "  Freeze panes command on the window menu ",
            "optionC": "  Hold titles command on the edit menu ",
            "optionD": "  Split command on the window menu ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we want to scroll down the worksheet, and lock the heading rows in place, so it is always visible, we can use one of the Freeze Panes commands.",
            "keyString": "121906s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To edit in an embedded excel worksheet object in a word document",
            "optionA": "  Use the excel menu bar and toolbars inside the word application ",
            "optionB": "  Edit the hyperlink ",
            "optionC": "  Edit the data in a excel source application ",
            "optionD": "  Use the word menu bar and toolbars ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tUse the excel menu bar and toolbars inside the word application to edit in an embedded excel worksheet object in a word document. ",
            "keyString": "121919s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To create a formula, you can use:",
            "optionA": "  Values but not cell references ",
            "optionB": "  Cell references but not values ",
            "optionC": "  Values or cell references although not both at the same time ",
            "optionD": "  Value and cell references ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo create a formula, we can use value and cell references both. ",
            "keyString": "121931s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Excel displays the current cell address in the ________",
            "optionA": "  Formula bar ",
            "optionB": "  Status Bar ",
            "optionC": "  Name Box ",
            "optionD": "  Title Bar ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tName Box refers to an input box directly to the left of the formula bar. The Name Box normally displays the address of the \"active cell\" on the worksheet. You can also use the name box to quickly create a named range. ",
            "keyString": "171774s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the correct way to refer the cell A10 on sheet3 from sheet1?",
            "optionA": "  Sheet3!A10 ",
            "optionB": "  Sheet1!A10 ",
            "optionC": "  Sheet3.A10 ",
            "optionD": "  A10 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFirst we use the name of sheet, then put an exclamation mark, at the end give the cell reference. It would be look like =Sheet3!A10",
            "keyString": "171809s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which language is used to create macros in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Visual Basic ",
            "optionB": "  C ",
            "optionC": "  Visual C++ ",
            "optionD": "  Java ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVBA (Visual Basic for Applications) is the programming language of Excel with VBA we can automate tasks in Excel by writing so called macros. ",
            "keyString": "171824s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a term of MS-Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Cells ",
            "optionB": "  Rows ",
            "optionC": "  Columns ",
            "optionD": "  Document ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA worksheet in Excel is made up of Rows and Columns. Intersection of a Row and column in an Excel worksheet is a rectangle called as a Cell. Cells store a value, a formula, or text. ",
            "keyString": "171836s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How many worksheets can a workbook have?",
            "optionA": "  3 ",
            "optionB": "  8 ",
            "optionC": "  255 ",
            "optionD": "  none of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel does not limit the number of sheets, so it is only limited by available memory on your computer (RAM). This means the max number of sheets is higher on computers with more memory. ",
            "keyString": "171849s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a popular DOS based spreadsheet package?",
            "optionA": "  Word ",
            "optionB": "  Smart cell ",
            "optionC": "  Excel ",
            "optionD": "  Lotus 1-2-3 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLotus 1-2-3 spreadsheet was the first MS-DOS based spreadsheet package which was released on January 26, 1983. It was the IBM PC's first killer application, was hugely popular in the 1980s, displacing the former leader VisiCalc and contributed significantly to the success of the IBM PC. Lotus had difficulties adapting 1-2-3 to the Windows environment, and was overtaken by Microsoft Excel. ",
            "keyString": "279600s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An excel workbook is a collection of",
            "optionA": "  Workbooks ",
            "optionB": "  Worksheets ",
            "optionC": "  Charts ",
            "optionD": "  Worksheets and charts ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA workbook is a collection of one or more spreadsheets and charts in a single file. ",
            "keyString": "279634s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Excel files have a default extension of in Excel-2003",
            "optionA": "  Xls ",
            "optionB": "  Xlw ",
            "optionC": "  Wk1 ",
            "optionD": "  123 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel files have a default extension of xls in 2003 and earlier version of MS-office and xlxs in 2007 and higher version of MS-office. ",
            "keyString": "279648s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use the format painter multiple times before you turn it off by",
            "optionA": "  You can use the format painter button on ly one time when you click it ",
            "optionB": "  Double clicking the format painter button ",
            "optionC": "  Pressing the Ctrl key and clicking the format painter button ",
            "optionD": "  Pressing the Alt key and clicking the format painter button ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can use the format painter multiple times before we turn it off by double clicking the format painter button. ",
            "keyString": "279661s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use the formula palette to",
            "optionA": "  Format cells containing numbers ",
            "optionB": "  Create and edit formulas containing functions ",
            "optionC": "  Enter assumptions data ",
            "optionD": "  Copy a range of cells ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFormula palette is used to create and edit formula. Itisalsopossibletotypeafunctiondirectlyintoacell,however,asthereareover300 functionsbuiltintoMicrosoftExcel,someofwhicharequitecomplex,Excelprovidesthe Formula Palette to simplify the process.",
            "keyString": "279673s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Comments put in cells are called",
            "optionA": "  Smart Tip ",
            "optionB": "  Cell Tip ",
            "optionC": "  Web Tip ",
            "optionD": "  Soft Tip ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tComments put in cells are called Cell Tip ",
            "keyString": "333461s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which is used to perform what if analysis?",
            "optionA": "  Solver ",
            "optionB": "  Goal seek ",
            "optionC": "  Scenario Manager ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGoal seek, Scenario Manager and Solver are used to perform what if analysis in Excel. ",
            "keyString": "333597s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use the horizontal and vertical scroll bars to",
            "optionA": "  Split a worksheet into two panes ",
            "optionB": "  View different rows and columns edit the contents of a cell ",
            "optionC": "  Edit the contents of a cell ",
            "optionD": "  View different worksheets ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tYou can use the horizontal and vertical scroll bars to view different rows and columns edit the contents of a cell. ",
            "keyString": "333646s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Multiple calculations can be made in a single formula using",
            "optionA": "  Standard formulas ",
            "optionB": "  Array formula ",
            "optionC": "  Complex formulas ",
            "optionD": "  Smart formula ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn array formula is a formula that can perform multiple calculations on one or more of the items in an array. We can think of an array as a row of values, a column of values, or a combination of rows and columns of values. Array formulas can return either multiple results or a single result. For example, we can create an array formula in a range of cells and use the array formula to calculate a column or row of subtotals. We can also place an array formula in a single cell and calculate a single amount. An array formula that includes multiple cells is called a multi-cell formula, and an array formula in a single cell is called a single-cell formula. ",
            "keyString": "333689s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Hyperlinks can be",
            "optionA": "  Text ",
            "optionB": "  Drawing objects ",
            "optionC": "  Pictures ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tHyperlinks can be a text or drawing objects or pictures. A hyperlink is a word, phrase, or image that we can click on to jump to a new file or a new section within the current file. ",
            "keyString": "333727s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To save a workbook, you:",
            "optionA": "  Click the save button on the standard toolbar from the menu ",
            "optionB": "  Press Ctrl+ F5 ",
            "optionC": "  Click Save on the Windows Start button ",
            "optionD": "  Select Edit > Save ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tClick the save button on the standard toolbar from the menu ",
            "keyString": "448726s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can edit a cell by",
            "optionA": "  Clicking the formula button ",
            "optionB": "  Double clicking the cell to edit it in-place ",
            "optionC": "  Selecting Edit > Edit Cell from the menu ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDouble clicking the cell to edit it in-place ",
            "keyString": "448865s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can select a single range of cells by",
            "optionA": "  Clicking the upper-left cell in a group of cells and then pressing the Shift key while clicking the lower right cell in a group of cells ",
            "optionB": "  Pressing the Ctrl key while dragging over the desired cells ",
            "optionC": "  Pressing the Shift key and an arrow key ",
            "optionD": "  Dragging over the desired cells ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can select a single range of cells by dragging cursor over the desired cells. ",
            "keyString": "448912s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which elements of worksheet can be protected from accidental modification",
            "optionA": "  Contents ",
            "optionB": "  Objects ",
            "optionC": "  Scenarios ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAll elements of a worksheet can be protected from accidental modification.To protect a worksheet in Excel 2007 and higher versions, click the Review tab, click Protect Worksheet (or Protect Sheet), and click OK.Excel 2003 and Earlier Versions click Tools > Protection, click Protect Sheet, and click OK. ",
            "keyString": "448956s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can use the drag and drop method to",
            "optionA": "  Copy cell contents ",
            "optionB": "  Move cell contents ",
            "optionC": "  Add cell contents ",
            "optionD": "  A and B both ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDrag-and-drop is a mouse technique that we can use in Excel to pick up a cell selection and drop it into a new place on the worksheet. Although drag and drop is primarily a technique for moving cell entries around a worksheet, we can also adapt it to copy a cell selection. ",
            "keyString": "448989s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following format you can decide to apply or not in AutoFormat dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Number format ",
            "optionB": "  Border format ",
            "optionC": "  Font format ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAutoFormat option in excel is a unique way of formatting data quickly, the first step is we need to select the entire data we need to format and then the second step we need to click on auto-format from the QAT and third step we need to choose the format from the different options.",
            "keyString": "508878s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you remove borders applied in cells?",
            "optionA": "  Choose None on Border tab of Format cells ",
            "optionB": "  Open the list on Border tool in Format Cell toolbar then choose first tool (none) ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOn the Home tab, in the Font group, click the arrow next to Borders Button, and then click No Border Button. --OR-- Click Home > the Borders arrow > Erase Border, and then select the cells with the border you want to erase. ",
            "keyString": "508972s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Where can you set the shading color for a range of cells in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Choose required color form Patterns tab of Format Cells dialog box ",
            "optionB": "  Choose required color on Fill Color tool in Formatting toolbar ",
            "optionC": "  Choose required color on Fill Color tool in Drawing toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe formatting and Drawing toolbar is a toolbar in Microsoft Office 2003 and earlier applications, that gives the user the ability to change the formatting of selected text or cell. ",
            "keyString": "508999s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can set Page Border in Excel from",
            "optionA": "  From Border tab in Format Cells dialog box ",
            "optionB": "  From Border tool in Formatting toolbar ",
            "optionC": "  From Line Style tool in Drawing toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  You can not set page border in Excel ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThere is no option to set page border in Excel.",
            "keyString": "509022s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When all the numbers between 0 and 100 in a range should be displayed in Red Color, apply",
            "optionA": "  Use =if() function to format the required numbers red ",
            "optionB": "  Apply Conditional Formatting command on Format menu ",
            "optionC": "  Select the cells that contain number between 0 and 100 then click Red color on Text Color tool ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA conditional format changes the appearance of cells on the basis of conditions that you specify. If the conditions are true, the cell range is formatted; if the conditions are false, the cell range is not formatted.",
            "keyString": "509044s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which area in an Excel window allows entering values and formulas?",
            "optionA": "  Title Bar ",
            "optionB": "  Menu Bar ",
            "optionC": "  Formula Bar ",
            "optionD": "  Standard Tool Bar ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:Formula Bar area in an Excel window allows entering values and formulas. Formula Bar is a toolbar at the top of the Microsoft Excel spreadsheet window that we can use to enter or copy an existing formula in to cells or charts. It is labeled with function symbol (fx). By clicking the Formula Bar, or when you type an equal (=) symbol in a cell, the Formula Bar will activate.",
            "keyString": "572052s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Multiple calculations can be made in a single formula using ________",
            "optionA": "  Standard Formulas ",
            "optionB": "  Array Formula ",
            "optionC": "  Complex Formulas ",
            "optionD": "  Smart Formula ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn array formula is a formula that can perform multiple calculations on one or more of the items in an array. We can think of an array as a row of values, a column of values, or a combination of rows and columns of values. Array formulas can return either multiple results or a single result. For example, we can create an array formula in a range of cells and use the array formula to calculate a column or row of subtotals. We can also place an array formula in a single cell and calculate a single amount. An array formula that includes multiple cells is called a multi-cell formula, and an array formula in a single cell is called a single-cell formula. ",
            "keyString": "572085s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "An Excel Workbook is a collection of ________",
            "optionA": "  Workbooks ",
            "optionB": "  Worksheets ",
            "optionC": "  Charts ",
            "optionD": "  Worksheets and Charts ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA workbook is a collection of one or more spreadsheets and charts in a single file. ",
            "keyString": "572100s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What do you mean by a Workspace?",
            "optionA": "  Group of Columns ",
            "optionB": "  Group of Worksheets ",
            "optionC": "  Group of Rows ",
            "optionD": "  Group of Workbooks ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe term workspace refers to all the open workbooks and their exact screen position and window sizes. A workspace contains pointers to your other Excel files that you had open during your session. When you open an Excel workspace all the other files are opened as well Workspaces are particularly useful if you frequently work with the same set of files and need to have them all open at once. ",
            "keyString": "572113s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "MS-EXCEL is based on ________",
            "optionA": "  WINDOWS ",
            "optionB": "  DOS ",
            "optionC": "  UNIX ",
            "optionD": "  OS/2 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMS-Excel is based on Windows. MS-Excel is a spreadsheet developed by Microsoft for Windows and few other operating systems. It is a program that stores and retrieves numerical data in rows and columns of grid format. ",
            "keyString": "572125s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the cell pointer indicates you that you can make selection?",
            "optionA": "  Doctor\u2019s symbol (Big Plus) ",
            "optionB": "  Small thin plus icon ",
            "optionC": "  Mouse Pointer with anchor at the tip ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDoctor\u2019s symbol (Big Plus) indicates we that we can make selection to cell.",
            "keyString": "627136s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the cell pointer indicates that you can fill series?",
            "optionA": "  Doctor\u2019s symbol (Big Plus) ",
            "optionB": "  Small thin plus icon ",
            "optionC": "  Mouse Pointer with anchor at the tip ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSmall thin plus iconcell pointer indicates that you can fill series. ",
            "keyString": "627171s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the cell pointer indicate that you can move the content to other cell?",
            "optionA": "  Doctor\u2019s symbol (Big Plus) ",
            "optionB": "  Small thin plus icon ",
            "optionC": "  Mouse Pointer with anchor at the tip ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMouse Pointer with anchor at the tip cell pointer indicate that you can move the content to other cell. ",
            "keyString": "627186s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can auto fit the width of column by",
            "optionA": "  Double clicking on the column name on column header ",
            "optionB": "  Double click on the cell pointer in worksheet ",
            "optionC": "  Double clicking on column right border on column header ",
            "optionD": "  Double clicking on the column left border of column header ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tYou can auto fit the width of column by double clicking on column right border on column header. ",
            "keyString": "627199s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Long text can be broken down into many lines within a cell. You can do this through",
            "optionA": "  Wrap Text in Format > Cells ",
            "optionB": "   Justify in Edit > Cells ",
            "optionC": "  Text Wrapping in Format > Cells ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Excel can wrap text so it appears on multiple lines in a cell. We can format the cell so the text wraps automatically, or enter a manual line break. On the Home tab, in the Alignment group, click Wrap Text. ",
            "keyString": "627212s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which would you choose to create a bar diagram?",
            "optionA": "  Edit, Chart ",
            "optionB": "  Insert, Chart ",
            "optionC": "  Tools, Chart ",
            "optionD": "  Format, Chart ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tClick the Insert > Chart ",
            "keyString": "678104s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which setting you must modify to print a worksheet using letterhead?\n",
            "optionA": "  Paper ",
            "optionB": "  Margin ",
            "optionC": "  Layout ",
            "optionD": "  Orientation ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe need to set margins in Excel worksheets before printing, open the \u201cPage Setup\u201d dialog box. To open the \u201cPage Setup\u201d dialog box, click the \u201cPage Layout\u201d tab in the Ribbon. ",
            "keyString": "678136s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What do you call the chart that shows the proportions of how one or more data elements relate to another data element?\n",
            "optionA": "  XY Chart ",
            "optionB": "  Line Chart ",
            "optionC": "  Pie Chart ",
            "optionD": "  Column Chart ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tScatter plot (XY chart) used to show scientific XY data. Scatter plots are often used to find out if there's a relationship between variable X and Y. Line charts are used to display trends over time. Use a line chart if you have text labels, dates or a few numeric labels on the horizontal axis.Pie charts are used to display the contribution of each value (slice) to a total (pie). Pie charts always use one data series. Column charts are used to compare values across categories by using vertical bars. ",
            "keyString": "678151s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The spelling dialog box can be involved by choosing spelling from ________ menu.",
            "optionA": "  Insert ",
            "optionB": "  File ",
            "optionC": "  Tools ",
            "optionD": "  View ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel 2003 and earlier version Tools > Spelling From Excel 2007 and higher version Ribbon > Review tab > Proofing group > Spelling ",
            "keyString": "678165s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which key do you press to check spelling?",
            "optionA": "  F3 ",
            "optionB": "  F5 ",
            "optionC": "  F7 ",
            "optionD": "  F9 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn most Microsoft Office apps (including Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook), tap F7 to begin the spellcheck process. ",
            "keyString": "678177s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Status indicators are located on the",
            "optionA": "  Vertical scroll bar ",
            "optionB": "  Horizontal scroll bar ",
            "optionC": "  Formula bar ",
            "optionD": "  Standard toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tStatus indicators are located on the formula bar. ",
            "keyString": "723599s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the oldest spreadsheet package?",
            "optionA": "  VisiCalc ",
            "optionB": "  Lotus 1-2-3 ",
            "optionC": "  Excel ",
            "optionD": "  StarCalc ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tVisiCalc was the first computer spreadsheet program. It was released to the public in 1979, running on an Apple II computer. While most early microprocessor computers had been quickly supported by BASIC and a few games, VisiCalc introduced a new level in application software. It was considered a fourth generation software program.",
            "keyString": "723634s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Rounding errors can occur",
            "optionA": "  When you use multiplication, division, or exponentiation in a formula ",
            "optionB": "  When you use addition and subtraction in a formula ",
            "optionC": "  Because excel uses hidden decimal places in computation ",
            "optionD": "  When you show the results of formulas with different decimal places that the calculated results ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we use multiplication, division, or exponentiation in a formula, rounding errors can occur. ",
            "keyString": "723648s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can copy data or formulas",
            "optionA": "  With the copy, paste and cut commands on the edit menu ",
            "optionB": "  With commands on the shortcut menu ",
            "optionC": "  With buttons on the standard toolbars ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can copy data or formulas with the copy, paste and cut commands on the edit menu or with commands on the shortcut menu or with buttons on the standard toolbars in Excel 2003 or earlier version. ",
            "keyString": "723660s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You cannot link excel worksheet data to a word document",
            "optionA": "  With the right drag method ",
            "optionB": "  With a hyperlink ",
            "optionC": "  With the copy and paste special commands ",
            "optionD": "  With the copy and paste buttons on the standard toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe cannot link excel worksheet data to a word document with the copy and paste buttons on the standard toolbar. ",
            "keyString": "723671s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A worksheet can have a maximum of ________ number of rows.",
            "optionA": "  256 ",
            "optionB": "  1024 ",
            "optionC": "  65535 ",
            "optionD": "  1048576 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel 2003 and earlier 65,536 Rows.Excel 2007 and higher 1,048,576 Rows.",
            "keyString": "765377s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of a value?",
            "optionA": "  350 ",
            "optionB": "  May 10, 2001 ",
            "optionC": "  0.57 ",
            "optionD": "  Serial Number 50771 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSerial Number 50771 is alpha numeric can not be considered as value.",
            "keyString": "765462s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The chart wizard term data series refers to",
            "optionA": "  A chart legend ",
            "optionB": "  A collection of chart data markers ",
            "optionC": "  A set of values you plot in a chart ",
            "optionD": "  A data label ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe chart wizard term data series refers to a collection of chart data markers. ",
            "keyString": "765486s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Chart wizard term data categories refers to;",
            "optionA": "  A chart plot area ",
            "optionB": "  A horizontal axis ",
            "optionC": "  The organization of individual values with a chart\u2019s data series ",
            "optionD": "  The data range that supply chart data ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Chart wizard term data categories refers to a horizontal axis. ",
            "keyString": "765517s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A worksheet range is a",
            "optionA": "  A command used for data modeling ",
            "optionB": "  A range of values such as from 23 to 234 ",
            "optionC": "  A group of cells ",
            "optionD": "  A group of worksheets ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA worksheet range is a group of cells. ",
            "keyString": "765549s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following series type is not valid for Fill Series dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Linear ",
            "optionB": "  Growth ",
            "optionC": "  Autofill ",
            "optionD": "  Time ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTime series type is not valid for Fill Series dialog box in excel. ",
            "keyString": "821507s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following you can paste selectively using Paste Special command?",
            "optionA": "  Validation ",
            "optionB": "  Formats ",
            "optionC": "  Formulas ",
            "optionD": "  All of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can paste formula, value, formats, comments, validation using Paste Special command.",
            "keyString": "821553s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Paste Special allows some operation while you paste to new cell. Which of the following operation is valid?",
            "optionA": "  Square ",
            "optionB": "  Percentage ",
            "optionC": "  Goal Seek ",
            "optionD": "  Divide ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPaste Special allows Divide operation while you paste to new cell.",
            "keyString": "821683s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Edit > Delete command",
            "optionA": "  Deletes the content of a cell ",
            "optionB": "  Deletes Formats of cell ",
            "optionC": "  Deletes the comment of cell ",
            "optionD": "  Deletes selected cells ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDeletes selected cells through Edit > Delete command was available in Excel 2003 and earlier versions.",
            "keyString": "821791s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To remove the content of selected cells you must issue ______ command",
            "optionA": "  Delete ",
            "optionB": "  Clear Contents ",
            "optionC": "  Clear All ",
            "optionD": "  Clear Delete ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo remove the content of selected cells we must issue Clear Contents command. Clear Contents will clear only the data, will not clear any formats. ",
            "keyString": "822222s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you copy a formula",
            "optionA": "  Excel erases the original copy of the formula ",
            "optionB": "  Excel edits cell references in the newly copied formula ",
            "optionC": "  Excel adjusts absolute cell references ",
            "optionD": "  Excel doesn\u2019t adjust relative cell references ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen you copy a formula Excel edits cell references in the newly copied formula. ",
            "keyString": "865734s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The autofill feature",
            "optionA": "  Extends a sequential series of data ",
            "optionB": "  Automatically adds range of cell values ",
            "optionC": "  Applies a boarder around the selected cells ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAutoFill feature of Excel is a great time saver. This command can automatically extend the sequence, adds range of cell values, applies a boarder around the selected cells. ",
            "keyString": "865780s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which menu option can be used to split windows into two",
            "optionA": "  Format > window ",
            "optionB": "  View > window > split ",
            "optionC": "  Window > split ",
            "optionD": "  View > split ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:View > Window > Split option can be used to split windows into two. ",
            "keyString": "865886s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is an absolute cell reference?",
            "optionA": "  !A!1 ",
            "optionB": "  $A$1 ",
            "optionC": "  #a#1 ",
            "optionD": "  A1 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe absolute cell reference in excel is a cell address that contains a dollar sign ($). It can precede the column reference, the row reference or both.",
            "keyString": "865988s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What symbol is used before a number to make it a label?",
            "optionA": "   \u201d ( quote ) ",
            "optionB": "  = ( equal ) ",
            "optionC": "  _ ( underscore ) ",
            "optionD": "  \u2018 ( apostrophe ) ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn apostrophe before a cell value forces Excel to interpret the value as label. This is mostly useful for values that look like a number or date. ",
            "keyString": "866083s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To record a sequence of keystrokes and mouse actions to play back later we use:",
            "optionA": "  Media player ",
            "optionB": "  Sound Recorder ",
            "optionC": "  Calculator ",
            "optionD": "  Macro Recorder ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMacro Recorder records your mouse movements, mouse clicks and keyboard input. Just like a tape recorder for your computer. ",
            "keyString": "909241s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "We can save and protect the workbook by",
            "optionA": "  Write Reservation Password ",
            "optionB": "  Protection Password ",
            "optionC": "  Read-only Recommended ",
            "optionD": "  Any of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can save and protect the workbook by Encrypt a Workbook with a Password, Make a Workbook Read-Only, Protect a Workbook\u2019s Structure, Protect a Worksheet from Editing, Protect Specific Cells From Editing.",
            "keyString": "909280s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The first cell in EXCEL worksheet is labeled as",
            "optionA": "  AA ",
            "optionB": "  A1 ",
            "optionC": "  Aa ",
            "optionD": "  A0 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe first cell in EXCEL worksheet is labeled as A1.",
            "keyString": "909387s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What happens when dollar signs ($) are entered in a cell address? (e$B$2:$B$10)",
            "optionA": "  An absolute cell address is created ",
            "optionB": "  Cell address will change when it is copied to another cell ",
            "optionC": "  The sheet tab is changed ",
            "optionD": "  The status bar does not display the cell address ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe absolute cell reference in excel is a cell address that contains a dollar sign ($). It can precede the column reference, the row reference or both.",
            "keyString": "909485s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What are the tabs that appear at the bottom of each workbook called?",
            "optionA": "  Reference tabs ",
            "optionB": "  Position tabs ",
            "optionC": "  Location tabs ",
            "optionD": "  Sheet tabs ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel, a sheet, sheet tab, or worksheet tab is used to display the worksheet that a user is currently editing. By clicking a worksheet tab (located at the bottom of the workbook), users may move between the various worksheets. ",
            "keyString": "909583s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you delete a column?",
            "optionA": "  Select the column heading you want to delete and select the Delete Row button on the standard toolbar ",
            "optionB": "  Select the column heading you want to delete and select Insert Delete from the menu ",
            "optionC": "  Select the row heading you want to delete and select Edit>Delete from the menu ",
            "optionD": "  Right click the column heading you want to delete and select delete from the shortcut menu ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRight click the column heading you want to delete and select delete from the shortcut menu in Excel 2003.From 2007 and Higher version Home > Delete > Delete Sheet Columns. ",
            "keyString": "956968s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you find specific information in a list?",
            "optionA": "  Select Tools > Finder from the menu ",
            "optionB": "  Click the Find button on the standard toolbar ",
            "optionC": "  Select Insert > Find from the menu ",
            "optionD": "  Select Data > Form from the menu to open the Data Form dialog box and click the Criteria button ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSelect Data > Form from the menu to open the Data Form dialog box and click the Criteria button ",
            "keyString": "957015s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When integrating word and excel, word is usually the",
            "optionA": "  Server ",
            "optionB": "  Destination ",
            "optionC": "  Client ",
            "optionD": "  Both b and c ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen integrating ms-word and excel, word is usually the Destination and Client . ",
            "keyString": "957144s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a label is too long to fit within a worksheet cell, you typically must",
            "optionA": "  Shorten the label ",
            "optionB": "  Increase the column width ",
            "optionC": "  Decrease the column width ",
            "optionD": "  Adjust the row height ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen a label is too long to fit within a worksheet cell, we must increase the column width. ",
            "keyString": "957244s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The name box",
            "optionA": "  Shows the location of the previously active cell ",
            "optionB": "  Appears to the left of the formula bar ",
            "optionC": "  Appears below the status bar ",
            "optionD": "  Appears below the menu bar ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tName Box refers to an input box directly to the left of the formula bar. The Name Box normally displays the address of the \"active cell\" on the worksheet. You can also use the name box to quickly create a named range. ",
            "keyString": "957343s14m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Paste Special command lets you copy and paste:",
            "optionA": "  Multiply the selection by a copied value ",
            "optionB": "  Cell comments ",
            "optionC": "  Formatting options ",
            "optionD": "  The resulting values of a formula instead of the actual formula ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Paste Special command lets you copy and paste the resulting values of a formula instead of the actual formula. ",
            "keyString": "9763s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The numbers in our worksheet look like this 1000: You want them to look like this: $1,000.How can you accomplish this?",
            "optionA": "  You have to retype everything and manually add the dollar signs, commas, and decimals ",
            "optionB": "  Select Format > Money from the menu ",
            "optionC": "  Click the Currency Style button on the formatting toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  None of these ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tClick the Currency Style button on the formatting toolbar ",
            "keyString": "9808s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Excel worksheet cells work very similarly to what common element of the windows graphical user interface",
            "optionA": "  Option buttons ",
            "optionB": "  List boxes ",
            "optionC": "  Text boxes ",
            "optionD": "  Combo boxes ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel worksheet cells work very similarly to Text boxes graphical user interface. ",
            "keyString": "9917s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following options is not located in the Page Setup dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Page Break Preview ",
            "optionB": "  Page Orientation ",
            "optionC": "  Margins ",
            "optionD": "  Headers and Footers ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution: ",
            "keyString": "10032s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You want to track the progress of the stock market on a daily basis. Which type of chart should you use?",
            "optionA": "  Pie chart ",
            "optionB": "  Row chart ",
            "optionC": "  Line chart ",
            "optionD": "  Column chart ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA line chart is the most basic and simplest type of stock charts that are used in technical analysis. The line chart is also called a close-only chart as it plots the closing price of the underlying security, with a line connecting the dots formed by the close price. ",
            "keyString": "10130s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following Excel screen components can NOT be turned on or off?",
            "optionA": "  Formula Bar ",
            "optionB": "  Status Bar ",
            "optionC": "  Tool Bar ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tShow Formula bar option by clicking the File (or Office button) > Options > Advanced > Display > Show Formula bar. In earlier versions of Excel, you could hide the status bar if you wanted more space available for your worksheets. However, that capability was removed starting with Excel 2007.In earlier versions of Excel, you could hide the tool bar as per requirement. However, that capability was removed starting with Excel 2007 and introduced Ribbon. ",
            "keyString": "62736s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What happens when you press Ctrl + X after selecting some cells in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  The cell content of selected cells disappear from cell and stored in clipboard ",
            "optionB": "  The cells selected are marked for cutting ",
            "optionC": "  The selected cells are deleted and the cells are shifted left ",
            "optionD": "  The selected cells are deleted and cells are shifted up ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we pressing the ctrl+x in the Microsoft excel sheet it means we cut the content from that cell simply means the cells selected are marked for cutting and the user has need to move the content from one cell to another cell. ",
            "keyString": "63141s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following option is not available in Paste Special dialog box?",
            "optionA": "  Add ",
            "optionB": "  Subtract ",
            "optionC": "  Divide ",
            "optionD": "  SQRT ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo use options from the Paste Special box, click Home > Paste > Paste Special.",
            "keyString": "63217s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which command will you choose to convert a column of data into row?",
            "optionA": "  Cut and Paste ",
            "optionB": "  Paste Special > Transpose ",
            "optionC": "  Both of above ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTranspose (rotate) data from rows to columns or vice versa. To use options from the Paste Special box, click Home > Paste > Paste Special > Transpose",
            "keyString": "63239s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "It is acceptable to let long text flow into adjacent cells on a worksheet when",
            "optionA": "  Data will be entered in the adjacent cells ",
            "optionB": "  No data will be entered in the adjacent cells ",
            "optionC": "  There is no suitable abbreviation for the text ",
            "optionD": "  There is not time to format the text ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen there is no data in in the adjacent cells, long text flows into adjacent cells on a worksheet. As soon as data is entered into in the adjacent cells, text will be visible upto cell length in which data is entered, For full visibility of data either we need to increase the length of cell or wrap text in particular cell. ",
            "keyString": "63265s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "MS Excel provides the default value for step in Fill Series dialog box",
            "optionA": "  0 ",
            "optionB": "  1 ",
            "optionC": "  5 ",
            "optionD": "  10 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe default value for any series is 1 in Excel. ",
            "keyString": "113908s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When a row of data is to be converted into columns",
            "optionA": "  Copy the cells in row, select the same number of cells in row and paste ",
            "optionB": "  Copy the cells in column then choose Paste Special, then click Transpose and OK ",
            "optionC": "  Copy the cells then go to Cells then on Alignment tab click Transpose check box and click OK ",
            "optionD": "  Select the cells then place the cell pointer on new cell and choose Paste Special, mark Transpose check box and click OK ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTranspose (rotate) data from rows to columns or vice versa. To use options from the Paste Special box, click Home > Paste > Paste Special > Transpose Select the cells then place the cell pointer on new cell and choose Paste Special, mark Transpose check box and click OK",
            "keyString": "114011s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Ctrl + D shortcut key in Excel will",
            "optionA": "  Open the font dialog box ",
            "optionB": "  Apply double underline for the active cell ",
            "optionC": "  Fill down in the selection ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCtrl+D fills the cell beneath with the contents of the selected cell in a column. To fill more than one cell, select the source cell and press Ctrl+Shift+Down to select all cells. Then press Ctrl+D to fill them with the contents of the original cell. ",
            "keyString": "114041s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The shortcut key Ctrl + R is used in Excel to",
            "optionA": "  Right align the content of cell ",
            "optionB": "  Remove the cell contents of selected cells ",
            "optionC": "  Fill the selection with active cells to the right ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCtrl+R fills the row cell to the right with the contents of the selected cell. To fill more than one cell, select the source cell and press Ctrl+Shift+Right arrow to select multiple cells. Then press Ctrl+R to fill them with the contents of the original cell. ",
            "keyString": "114063s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The command Edit > Fill Across Worksheet is active only when",
            "optionA": "  One sheet is selected ",
            "optionB": "  When many sheets are selected ",
            "optionC": "  When no sheet is selected ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tClick the Fill button in the Editing group, and then click Across Worksheet a command only appears when we have multiple worksheets selected. ",
            "keyString": "114090s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Each excel file is called a workbook because\n",
            "optionA": "  It can contain text and data ",
            "optionB": "  It can be modified ",
            "optionC": "  It can contain many sheets including worksheets and chart sheets ",
            "optionD": "  You have to work hard to create it ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA workbook is a collection of one or more spreadsheets and charts in a single file. ",
            "keyString": "158189s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Excel probably considers the cell entry January 1, 2020 to be a",
            "optionA": "  Label ",
            "optionB": "  Value ",
            "optionC": "  Formula ",
            "optionD": "  Text string ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel Date format is considered as value. ",
            "keyString": "158221s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can enter which types of data into worksheet cells?",
            "optionA": "  Labels, values, and formulas ",
            "optionB": "  Labels and values but not formulas ",
            "optionC": "  Values and formulas but not labels ",
            "optionD": "  Formulas only ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWe can enter Labels, values, and formulas into worksheet cells. ",
            "keyString": "158236s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "All worksheet formula",
            "optionA": "  Manipulate values ",
            "optionB": "  Manipulate labels ",
            "optionC": "  Return a formula result ",
            "optionD": "  Use the addition operator ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAll worksheet formula returns a formula result. ",
            "keyString": "158249s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is a correct order of precedence in formula calculation?",
            "optionA": "  Multiplication and division exponentiation positive and negative values ",
            "optionB": "  Multiplication and division, positive and negative values, addition and subtraction ",
            "optionC": "  Addition and subtraction, positive and negative values, exponentiation ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNone of above is correct order of precedence in formula calculation. ",
            "keyString": "158261s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which tool you will use to join some cells and place the content at the middle of joined cell?",
            "optionA": "  From Format Cells dialog box click on Merge Cells check box ",
            "optionB": "  From Format Cells dialog box select the Centered alignment ",
            "optionC": "  From Format Cells dialog box choose Merge and Center check box ",
            "optionD": "  Click on Merge and Center tool on formatting toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn 2003 and earlier versions -From Format Cells dialog box click on Merge Cells check box In 2007 and subsequent versions - Merge & Center icon on the Home ribbon. ",
            "keyString": "197080s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Tab scroll buttons are place on Excel screen",
            "optionA": "  Towards the bottom right corner ",
            "optionB": "  Towards the bottom left corner ",
            "optionC": "  Towards the top right corner ",
            "optionD": "  Towards the top left corner ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOn the bottom left of the worksheet we find the Sheet Tab Scroll Buttons to move to the First sheet, Previous sheet, Next sheet, and Last sheet.They are followed by the tabs for the worksheets in our workbook and the Insert Worksheet button or tab, depending on the version of Excel we are using.",
            "keyString": "197117s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Name box on to the left of formula bar",
            "optionA": "  Shows the name of workbook currently working on ",
            "optionB": "  Shows the name of worksheet currently working on ",
            "optionC": "  Shows the name of cell or range currently working on ",
            "optionD": "  None of above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tName Box refers to an input box directly to the left of the formula bar. The Name Box normally displays the address of the \"active cell\" on the worksheet. You can also use the name box to quickly create a named range. ",
            "keyString": "197134s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Each excel file is a workbook that contains different sheets. Which of the following can not be a sheet in workbook?",
            "optionA": "  Work sheet ",
            "optionB": "  Chart sheet ",
            "optionC": "  Macro sheet ",
            "optionD": "  Data sheet ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tData sheet can not be a sheet in workbook. ",
            "keyString": "197150s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not the correct method of editing the cell content?",
            "optionA": "  Press the Alt key ",
            "optionB": "  Press the F2 key ",
            "optionC": "  Click the formula bar ",
            "optionD": "  Double click the cell ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA cell can be edited through Press the F2 key or Click the formula bar or Double click the cell. ",
            "keyString": "197167s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Without using the mouse or the arrow keys, what is the fastest way of getting to cell A1 in a spreadsheet?",
            "optionA": "  Press Ctrl + Home ",
            "optionB": "  Press Home ",
            "optionC": "  Press Shift + Home ",
            "optionD": "  Press Alt + Home ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:Ctrl + Home key is the fastest way of getting to cell A1 in a spreadsheet. ",
            "keyString": "234956s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following methods can not be used to edit the contents of a cell?",
            "optionA": "  Press the Alt key ",
            "optionB": "  Clicking the formula bar ",
            "optionC": "  Pressing the F2 key ",
            "optionD": "  Double clicking the cell ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA cell can be edited through Press the F2 key or Click the formula bar or Double click the cell. ",
            "keyString": "234989s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "If you begin typing an entry into a cell and then realize that you don't want your entry placed into a cell, you:",
            "optionA": "  Press the Erase key ",
            "optionB": "  Press Esc ",
            "optionC": "  Press the Enter button ",
            "optionD": "  Press the Edit Formula button ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPressing the Esc key while editing a cell aborts the operation and leaves the cell in it's original state. ",
            "keyString": "235004s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To view a cell comment\n",
            "optionA": "  Click the edit comment command on the insert menu ",
            "optionB": "  Click the display comment command on the window menu ",
            "optionC": "  Position the mouse pointer over the cell ",
            "optionD": "  Click the comment command on the view menu ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPosition the mouse pointer over the cell to view a cell comment. ",
            "keyString": "235018s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you want to insert a blank embedded excel object in a word document you can",
            "optionA": "  Click the object command on the insert menu ",
            "optionB": "  Click the office links button on the standard toolbar ",
            "optionC": "  Click the create worksheet button on the formatting toolbar ",
            "optionD": "  Click the import excel command on the file menu ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFor inserting a blank embedded excel object in a word document we can click the object command on the insert menu. ",
            "keyString": "235030s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "It is acceptable to let long text flow into adjacent cells on a worksheet when",
            "optionA": "  Data will be entered in the adjacent cells ",
            "optionB": "  No data will be entered in the adjacent cells ",
            "optionC": "  There is no suitable abbreviation of the text ",
            "optionD": "  There is not time to format the next ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen there is no data in in the adjacent cells, long text flows into adjacent cells on a worksheet. As soon as data is entered into in the adjacent cells, text will be visible upto cell length in which data is entered, For full visibility of data either we need to increase the length of cell or wrap text in particular cell. ",
            "keyString": "274050s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you delete a record?",
            "optionA": "  Delete the column from the worksheet ",
            "optionB": "  Select Data > Form from the menu to open the Data Form dialog box, find the record and Click the Delete button ",
            "optionC": "  Select Data > Delete Record from the menu ",
            "optionD": "  Click the Delete button on the Standard toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSelect Data > Form from the menu to open the Data Form dialog box, find the record and Click the Delete button in Excel 2003 and earlier version. ",
            "keyString": "274084s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Right clicking something in Excel:",
            "optionA": "  Deletes the object ",
            "optionB": "  Nothing the right mouse button is there for left handed people ",
            "optionC": "  Opens a shortcut menu listing everything you can do to the object ",
            "optionD": "  Selects the object ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRight clicking something in Excel opens a shortcut menu listing everything you can do to the object. ",
            "keyString": "274098s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Documentation should include",
            "optionA": "  Destination and users of the output data ",
            "optionB": "  Source of input data ",
            "optionC": "  Information on the purpose of the workbook ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDocumentation should include Source of input data Destination and users of the output data Information on the purpose of the workbook. ",
            "keyString": "274112s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Files created with Lotus 1-2-3 have an extension",
            "optionA": "  DOC ",
            "optionB": "  XLS ",
            "optionC": "  123 ",
            "optionD": "  WK1 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLotus 1-2-3 have an extension .123 ",
            "keyString": "274126s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Getting data from a cell located in a different sheet is called ________",
            "optionA": "  Accessing ",
            "optionB": "  Referencing ",
            "optionC": "  Updating ",
            "optionD": "  Functioning ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGetting data from a cell located in a different sheet is called Cell reference. There are Three types of Cell reference in ExcelRelativeAbsoluteMixed",
            "keyString": "312777s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid data type in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Number ",
            "optionB": "  Character ",
            "optionC": "  Label ",
            "optionD": "  Date/Time ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThere are Three types of data in cells: labels, values, and formulas. Labels (text) are descriptive pieces of information, such as names, months, or other identifying statistics, and they usually include alphabetic characters. Values (numbers) are generally raw numbers or dates. Formulas are instructions for Excel to perform calculations. ",
            "keyString": "312810s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which elements of a worksheet can be protected from accidental modification?",
            "optionA": "  Contents ",
            "optionB": "  Objects ",
            "optionC": "  Scenarios ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAll elements of a worksheet can be protected from accidental modification.To protect a worksheet in Excel 2007 and higher versions, click the Review tab, click Protect Worksheet (or Protect Sheet), and click OK.Excel 2003 and Earlier Versions click Tools > Protection, click Protect Sheet, and click OK. ",
            "keyString": "312825s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A numeric value can be treated as label value if ________ precedes it.",
            "optionA": "  Apostrophe ( \u2018 ) ",
            "optionB": "  Exclamation ( ! ) ",
            "optionC": "  Hash ( # ) ",
            "optionD": "  Tilde ( ~ ) ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn apostrophe before a cell value forces Excel to interpret the value as text. This is mostly useful for values that look like a number or date. ",
            "keyString": "312838s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Concatenation of text can be done using",
            "optionA": "  Apostrophe ( \u2018 ) ",
            "optionB": "  Exclamation ( ! ) ",
            "optionC": "  Hash ( # )  ",
            "optionD": "  Ampersand ( & ) ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe ampersand (&) calculation operator allow us join text items without using a function. For example, =A1 & B1 will return the same value as =CONCATENATE(A1,B1). In many cases, using the ampersand operator is quicker and simpler than using CONCATENATE to create strings. ",
            "keyString": "312850s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a basic step in creating a worksheet?",
            "optionA": "  Save workbook ",
            "optionB": "  Modifiy the worksheet ",
            "optionC": "  Enter text and data ",
            "optionD": "  Copy the worksheet ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCopy the worksheet is not a basic step in creating a worksheet. ",
            "keyString": "350769s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you select an entire column?",
            "optionA": "  Select Edit > Select > Column from the menu ",
            "optionB": "  Click the column heading letter ",
            "optionC": "  Hold down the shift key as you click anywhere in the column ",
            "optionD": "  Hold down the Ctrl key as you click anywhere in the column ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo select an entire column in MS-EXCEL, Click the column heading letter or press CTRL + Space Bar key. ",
            "keyString": "350800s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How can you print three copies of a workbook?",
            "optionA": "  Select File > Properties form the menu and type 3 in the Copies to print text box ",
            "optionB": "  Select File > Print from the menu and type 3 in the Number of copies text box ",
            "optionC": "  Click the Print button on the standard toolbar to print the document then take it to Kinko\u2019s and have 2 more copies made ",
            "optionD": "  Press Ctrl+P+3 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSelect File > Print from the menu and type 3 in the Number of copies text box ",
            "keyString": "350815s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To create a formula, you first:",
            "optionA": "  Select the cell you want to place the formula into ",
            "optionB": "  Type the equals sign (=) to tell Excel that you\u2019re about to enter a formula ",
            "optionC": "  Enter the formula using any input values and the appropriate mathematical operators that make up your formula ",
            "optionD": "  Choose the new command from the file menu ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA formula always starts with an equal sign (=), which can be followed by numbers, math operators (such as a plus or minus sign), and functions, which can really expand the power of a formula. ",
            "keyString": "350827s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To center worksheet titles across a range of cells, you must",
            "optionA": "  Select the cells containing the title text plus the range over which the title text is to be centered ",
            "optionB": "  Widen the columns ",
            "optionC": "  Select the cells containing the title text plus the range over which the title text is to be enfettered ",
            "optionD": "  Format the cells with the comma style ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSelect the cells containing the title text plus the range over which the title text is to be centered ",
            "keyString": "350840s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which symbol must all formula begin with?",
            "optionA": "  = ",
            "optionB": "  + ",
            "optionC": "  ( ",
            "optionD": "  @ ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA formula always starts with an equal sign (=), which can be followed by numbers, math operators (such as a plus or minus sign), and functions, which can really expand the power of a formula. ",
            "keyString": "426618s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following formulas is not entered correctly?\n",
            "optionA": "  =10+50 ",
            "optionB": "  =B7*B1 ",
            "optionC": "  =B7+14 ",
            "optionD": "  10+50 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA formula always starts with an equal sign (=), which can be followed by numbers, math operators (such as a plus or minus sign), and functions, which can really expand the power of a formula. Here in option D 10+50 there is no equal sign (=), so it is not correct. ",
            "keyString": "426650s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following formulas will Excel not be able to calculate?",
            "optionA": "  =SUM(Sales)-A3 ",
            "optionB": "  =SUM(A1:A5)*.5 ",
            "optionC": "  =SUM(A1:A5)/(10-10) ",
            "optionD": "  =SUM(A1:A5)-10 ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSUM function returns the sum of values supplied. These values can be numbers, cell references, ranges, arrays, and constants, in any combination. Here =SUM(Sales) is incorrect if it is not name of any range. ",
            "keyString": "426664s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A typical worksheet has ________ number of columns.",
            "optionA": "  128 ",
            "optionB": "  256 ",
            "optionC": "  1024 ",
            "optionD": "  16384 ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel 2003 and earlier 256 (as label 'IV') columns. Excel 2007 and higher 16,384 (as label 'XFD') columns.",
            "keyString": "426676s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How many characters can be typed in a single cell in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  256 ",
            "optionB": "  1024 ",
            "optionC": "  32767 ",
            "optionD": "  65535 ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA cell can contain 32,767 number of characters. ",
            "keyString": "426688s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To activate the previous cell in a pre-selected range, press",
            "optionA": "  The Alt key ",
            "optionB": "  The Tab key ",
            "optionC": "  The Enter key ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo go to previous cell we use Go To function Ctrl + G. ",
            "keyString": "466356s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which button do you click to add up a series of numbers?",
            "optionA": "  The autosum button ",
            "optionB": "  The Formula button ",
            "optionC": "  The quicktotal button ",
            "optionD": "  The total button ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAutoSum is a Microsoft Excel function that adds together a range of cells and displays the total in the cell below the selected range.",
            "keyString": "466388s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When the formula bar is active, you can see",
            "optionA": "  The edit formula button ",
            "optionB": "  The cancel button ",
            "optionC": "  The enter button ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThree buttons Cancel, Enter, and Function Wizard appear in the Formula bar. When the formula bar is active, we can see all. ",
            "keyString": "466403s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To copy formatting from one area in a worksheet and apply it to another area you would use:",
            "optionA": "  The Edit > Copy Format and Edit>Paste Format commands form the menu ",
            "optionB": "  The Copy and Apply Formatting dialog box, located under the Format > Copy and Apply menu ",
            "optionC": "  There is no way to copy and apply formatting in Excel \u2013 You have to do it manually ",
            "optionD": "  The Format Painter button on the standard toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Format Painter copies formatting from one place and applies it to another. The Format Painter button on the standard toolbar in Excel 2003 and earlier version. Home tab, in the Clipboard group, click Format Painter in 2007 and higher version. ",
            "keyString": "466416s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In a worksheet you can select",
            "optionA": "  The entire worksheet ",
            "optionB": "  Rows ",
            "optionC": "  Columns ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn a worksheet we can select cell or range of cells or rows or columns or entire worksheet. ",
            "keyString": "466429s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To delete an embedded objects, first",
            "optionA": "  Double click the object ",
            "optionB": "  Select the object by clicking it ",
            "optionC": "  Press the Shift + Delete keys ",
            "optionD": "  Select it and then press the delete key ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo delete an embedded objects, first select it and then press the delete key. ",
            "keyString": "510668s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Comments can be added to cells using",
            "optionA": "  Edit > Comments ",
            "optionB": "  Insert > Comments ",
            "optionC": "  File > Comments ",
            "optionD": "  View > Comments ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tComments can be added to cells using Insert > Comments.",
            "keyString": "510701s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not a worksheet design criterion?",
            "optionA": "  Efficiency ",
            "optionB": "  Aditibility ",
            "optionC": "  Description ",
            "optionD": "  Clarity ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDescription ",
            "keyString": "510717s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "To copy cell contents using drag and drop press the",
            "optionA": "  End key ",
            "optionB": "  Shift key ",
            "optionC": "  Ctrl key ",
            "optionD": "  Esc key ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTo copy cell contents using drag and drop press the Ctrl key else it will move the data. ",
            "keyString": "510732s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the latest version of Excel",
            "optionA": "  Excel 2007 ",
            "optionB": "  Excel 2016 ",
            "optionC": "  Excel 365 ",
            "optionD": "  Excel XP ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOffice 365, always receive updates to the latest version of Office. ",
            "keyString": "510745s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "You can convert existing excel worksheet data an charts to an HTML document by using",
            "optionA": "  FTP wizard ",
            "optionB": "  Internet assistant wizard ",
            "optionC": "  Intranet wizard ",
            "optionD": "  Import wizard ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe Internet Assistant for Excel is an add-in wizard that allows you to create and distribute Excel documents online for viewing with any popular browser. The Internet Assistant helps you convert your spreadsheet data to HTML format. It is designed for the 1997 and earlier versions of Excel.",
            "keyString": "549324s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A circular reference is",
            "optionA": "  Geometric modeling tool ",
            "optionB": "  A cell that points to a drawing object ",
            "optionC": "  A formula that either directly or indirectly depends on itself ",
            "optionD": "  Always erroneous ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA circular reference occurs when a formula directly or indirectly refers to its own cell. This causes the formula to use its result in the calculation, which can create errors.",
            "keyString": "549357s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of following is Not one of Excel's what-if function?",
            "optionA": "  Goal seek ",
            "optionB": "  Solver ",
            "optionC": "  Scenario manager ",
            "optionD": "  Auto Outline ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGoal seek, Scenario Manager and Solver are used to perform what if analysis in Excel. ",
            "keyString": "549373s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "When you insert an excel file into a word document. The data are",
            "optionA": "  Hyperlinked placed in a word table ",
            "optionB": "  Linked ",
            "optionC": "  Embedded ",
            "optionD": "  Use the word menu bar and toolbars ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tWhen we insert an excel file into a word document and keep the source file linkage when data is updated in source file update data in liked file also. The data are Linked. In Embedded objects file become part of document and does not get updated when source file is updated. ",
            "keyString": "549386s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not information you can specify using the solver?",
            "optionA": "  Input cells ",
            "optionB": "  Constraints ",
            "optionC": "  Target cell ",
            "optionD": "  Changing cells ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSolver is used to find an optimal (maximum or minimum) value for a formula in one cell \u2014 called the objective cell \u2014 subject to constraints, or limits, on the values of other formula cells on a worksheet. Solver works with a group of cells, called decision variables or simply variable cells that are used in computing the formulas in the objective and constraint cells. Versions of Solver prior to Excel 2007 referred to the objective cell as the \"target cell,\" and the decision variable cells as \"changing cells\" or \"adjustable cells\". ",
            "keyString": "549399s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you display current date only in MS Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Date () ",
            "optionB": "  Today () ",
            "optionC": "  Now () ",
            "optionD": "  Time () ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDATE - returns the serial date value for a date TODAY - returns today's date NOW - returns the current date and time TIME - assemble a proper time. ",
            "keyString": "586926s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you wrap the text in a cell?\n",
            "optionA": "  Format, cells, font ",
            "optionB": "  Format, cells, protection ",
            "optionC": "  Format, cells, number ",
            "optionD": "  Format, cells, alignment ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Excel can wrap text so it appears on multiple lines in a cell. We can format the cell so the text wraps automatically, or enter a manual line break. On the Home tab, in the Alignment group, click Wrap Text. ",
            "keyString": "586959s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does COUNTA () function do?",
            "optionA": "  Counts cells having alphabets ",
            "optionB": "  Counts empty cells ",
            "optionC": "  Counts cells having number ",
            "optionD": "  Counts non-empty cells ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tCOUNTA function counts cells containing any type of information, including error values. COUNTA function does not count empty cells. ",
            "keyString": "586975s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the short cut key to highlight the entire column?",
            "optionA": "  Ctrl + C ",
            "optionB": "  Ctrl + Enter ",
            "optionC": "  Ctrl + Page Up ",
            "optionD": "  Ctrl + Space Bar ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:Ctrl + Space Bar is the short cut key to highlight the entire column. ",
            "keyString": "586988s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In the formula, which symbol specifies the fixed columns or rows?",
            "optionA": "  $ ",
            "optionB": "  * ",
            "optionC": "  % ",
            "optionD": "  & ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe absolute cell reference in excel is a cell address that contains a dollar sign ($). It can precede the column reference, the row reference or both.",
            "keyString": "586999s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is represented by the small, black square in the lower-right corner of an active cell or range?",
            "optionA": "  Copy handle ",
            "optionB": "  Fill handle ",
            "optionC": "  Insert handle ",
            "optionD": "  Border ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFill handle is a feature to extend (and fill) a series of numbers, dates, or even text to a desired number of cells in Excel. In the active cell of the spreadsheet, the fill handle is a small black box at the bottom right corner, as shown in the image.",
            "keyString": "622927s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In Excel, a Data Series is defined as what?",
            "optionA": "  A type of chart ",
            "optionB": "  A cell reference ",
            "optionC": "  A collection of related data ",
            "optionD": "  A division of results ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn Excel, a Data Series is defined as a collection of related data. A data series is just a fancy name for a collection of related numbers in the same row, or the same column. ",
            "keyString": "622960s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In Excel, the Fill Color button on the Formatting toolbar is used for what?",
            "optionA": "  To insert a background ",
            "optionB": "  To add borders ",
            "optionC": "  To select a distribution of figures ",
            "optionD": "  To add shading or color to a cell range ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFill Color is used to add or change the background color or pattern of cells.",
            "keyString": "622975s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In help menu of Excel, which of the following tabs are found?",
            "optionA": "  Contents tab ",
            "optionB": "  Answer Wizard tab ",
            "optionC": "  Index tab ",
            "optionD": "  all of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIn help menu of Excel 2003, Contents tab, Answer Wizard tab, Index tab are available.",
            "keyString": "622988s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "A ________ is a grid with labeled columns and rows.",
            "optionA": "  Dialog box ",
            "optionB": "  Worksheet ",
            "optionC": "  Clipboard ",
            "optionD": "  Toolbar ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tA worksheet in Excel is made up of Rows and Columns grids. Intersection of a Row and column in an Excel worksheet is a rectangle called as a Cell. Cells store a value, a formula, or text. ",
            "keyString": "623000s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The active cell:",
            "optionA": "  Is defined by a bold border around the cell ",
            "optionB": "  Receives the data the user enters ",
            "optionC": "  It is the formula bar ",
            "optionD": "  Only A and B ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAn active cell is a rectangular box that highlights (a bold border around) the cell in a spreadsheet. An active cell helps identify what cell is being worked with and where data will be entered. ",
            "keyString": "662794s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which function is used to calculate depreciation, rates of return, future values and loan payment amounts?",
            "optionA": "  Logical ",
            "optionB": "  Math & Trigonometry ",
            "optionC": "  Statistical ",
            "optionD": "  Financial ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFinancial Functions are used to calculate depreciation, rates of return, future values and loan payment amounts. A list of Excel Financial Functions in Excel are: \u21d2Investment value functions including 1. FV 2. FVSCHEDULE 3. NPV 4. PV 5. RECEIVED 6. XNPV \u21d2Internal rate of return functions including 1. IRR 2. MIRR 3. XIRR \u21d2Asset depreciation functions including 1. AMORDEGRC 2. AMORLINC 3. DB 4. DDB 5. SLN 6. SYD 7. VDB \u21d2Payment functions including 1. CUMIPMT 2. CUMPRINC 3. IPMT 4. ISPMT 5. PMT 6. PPMT \u21d2Dollar conversion including 1. DOLLARDE 2. DOLLARFR \u21d2Yield functions including 1. YIELD 2. YIELDDISC 3. YIELDMAT 4. ODDFYIELD 5. ODDLYIELD 6. TBILLEO 7. TBILLYIELD \u21d2Price functions including 1. PRICE 2. PRICEDISC 3. PRICEMAT 4. ODDFPRICE 5. ODDLPRICE 6. TBILLPRICE",
            "keyString": "662828s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "B7:B9 indicates:",
            "optionA": "  Cells B7 and cell B9 only ",
            "optionB": "  Cells B7 through B9 ",
            "optionC": "  Cell B8 only ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tB7:B9 indicates a range of cell between Cells B7 through B9. ",
            "keyString": "662843s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The Cancel and Enter buttons appear in the:",
            "optionA": "  Title bar ",
            "optionB": "  Formula bar ",
            "optionC": "  Menu bar ",
            "optionD": "  Sheet tabs ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThree buttons Cancel, Enter, and Function Wizard appear in the Formula bar. ",
            "keyString": "662856s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following methods cannot be used to enter data in a cell",
            "optionA": "  Pressing an arrow key ",
            "optionB": "  Pressing the Tab key ",
            "optionC": "  Pressing the Esc key ",
            "optionD": "  Clicking on the formula bar ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tPressing the Esc key while editing a cell aborts the operation and leaves the cell in it's original state. ",
            "keyString": "662868s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Microsoft Excel is a powerful ________",
            "optionA": "  Word processing package ",
            "optionB": "  Spreadsheet package ",
            "optionC": "  Communication S/W Package ",
            "optionD": "  DBMS package ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMicrosoft Excel is Microsoft's general-purpose spreadsheet program for Windows, used for data analysis and display. It is commonly used in a business environment since it is part of the Microsoft Office package. Microsoft Excel is an extremely powerful tool, which is used by millions of people everyday. Functions tailored to a specific task can be programmed into Excel to extend its capabilities with customised analysis tools. ",
            "keyString": "700493s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you rearrange the data in ascending or descending order?",
            "optionA": "  Data, Sort ",
            "optionB": "  Data, Form ",
            "optionC": "  Data, Table ",
            "optionD": "  Data Subtotals ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSorting data in MS Excel rearranges the rows based on the contents of a particular column. We can also sort a table to put names in alphabetical order or ascending or descending order. Or, maybe we want to sort data by Amount from smallest to largest or largest to smallest. ",
            "keyString": "700526s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which Chart can be created in Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Area ",
            "optionB": "  Line ",
            "optionC": "  Pie ",
            "optionD": "  All of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tExcel offers the following major chart types \u2212 Column Chart Line Chart Pie Chart Doughnut Chart Bar Chart Area Chart XY (Scatter) Chart Bubble Chart Stock Chart Surface Chart Radar Chart Combo Chart ",
            "keyString": "700553s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What will be the output if you format the cell containing 5,436.8 as '#,##0.00' ?",
            "optionA": "  5430 ",
            "optionB": "  5436.80 ",
            "optionC": "  5436.8 ",
            "optionD": "  6.8 ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\t'#,##0.00' = 5436.80 ",
            "keyString": "700567s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "How do you display current date and time in MS Excel?",
            "optionA": "  Date () ",
            "optionB": "  Today () ",
            "optionC": "  Now () ",
            "optionD": "  Time () ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tDATE - returns the serial date value for a date TODAY - returns today's date NOW - returns the current date and time TIME - assemble a proper time. ",
            "keyString": "700580s15m48h11d14m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        }
    ]
}